If
a player. Moves. With
. The from
a poor. To Iraq during.
The Eighth Air.
The first move.
To noise to foo.
Amy.
When. This is above is not.
A battle front like no other in the
long history of Miami Times was. This
is an aircraft.
Of.
The in.
The working day begins as it will
then with the ground troops as much
a part of the book first
as a way. If you're
a mechanic you've got your own. You get
attached to it. But you know when your ship
goes out on
a mission you may never see it again. So
you do your work as well as it can be done
perfectly. Because you wouldn't want anything
to go wrong that would be your full.
Moon.
Today the bombs will be taken from these
bomb dumps somewhere in England and
a little to specific points in
Bill home southern Germany.
Old Moon Moon to
deliver them is the job of the Bomber Command
just appalling. It's one of the most
difficult and complicated
of military operations.
Of
a. General
purpose demolition bomb impact but our
body of fire seven hundred fifty miles an
hour fierce five inches of
armor plate destroying.
Everything it's always hundred pilots
somebody else another gators take their
places. The group commander Colonel Stanley
Rae steps up to the target map and for
the first time you learn where you're
going. Sometimes your face turns white when
you find out sometimes the feeling you
won't come back tightens your insides. Not
so long ago you were sitting like this in
a college or high school classroom
listening to perhaps even
a little sleepy. But you listen here. And
as you listen you don't have time to
think of yourself here fade you concentrate
on the mission type of formation
assembly point zero hour group the
target whether enemy fire and I'm
a black group back home if I was down in
enemy territory destroy equipment if taken
prisoner I give no information name
rank and serial number that's all.
These all the passengers with one way ticket.
And this is the crew of the Memphis.
Three hundred twenty four ninety first and
the bombardment. Just one plane and one
in ones Bob or in one group of
one wing of one Air Force out
of fifteen United States Army Air Force
as. Well fellows we've never had an
easy ride over there yet. And today won't
be any different the way Scott except
unfriendly So keep your eyes peeled don't
get excited and yell when you're talking
on the intercom save your ammunition and
make yourself count let me know what goes
on back there Quinlan just. Stay on the
ball going and still bring us back like
she's always done OK let's go.
They have completed twenty four missions
in this the toughest theater of
a war the big league of Sky fighter
their experience is priceless. So
if the Mensa spell comes back this afternoon
they will be sent to bring the vital
lessons they have learned to thousands
of aircrew men in training at home. Is
America.
This is
a battlefront like no other in this
or any warm the monster home is no
booming can only the roaring engine from
the bombs on going through the quiet
English countryside. Isn't there.
Wheels of the impulse to leave the soil
of Kingdom for the twenty fifth time and
the friendless for
a living will and with the support of
some rural families its country is very
surrounded by formal gardens and welcome
folks and the England these Americans knew
homely from the classics they have to read
into and big England of the towns and
cities and whose people have defended
the Highlands freedom for over
a thousand years and today is their
country's brightest chains and today their
island has been converted
into a gigantic bomb
a few super aircraft carrier taken off the
shores of procedure and with hangers and
machine shops with hundreds
of dispersal points
a limit of trucks concrete runways and
this is England in its fifth year of
warned. This is the new battle.
From which we seek out the enemy that is
infantry or is artillery that is perhaps
a bit greater. The industrial business
the foundation on which the map
the Empire army stand the power
and the drama class. The
steel mills and refineries shipyards and
submarines and factories and munitions
pinpoints on the map of Europe which
mean rubber. Bearings engines planes.
Targets to be destroyed. And these
are the destroy lives. Each with
ability. And ten men like the. Morgan
Hill and. The other.
Ministrations of the University
of Connecticut radio operator an.
Engineer in time to. Play
with guns used to be
a stevedore. Keeping the bill in order.
To your. Alter
ego. Of
a company. That
climbing higher now three hundred feet
a minute rain on the plains. The rest of
the group. Kept them in
the never operated. With
guns on the right. Company. On
the left not in town enough down
there was missing the point. Now we've.
Learned to. Make them.
Against the enemy by the.
Planes that cover every
gun. And down. To the
right. Range to overcome the
paint on aspiring in the.
Rain so. Demanding.
Thousand yards. In every direction.
Coast of England. Now. When you come back.
This will be the most you in the world.
I mean to reach your best operate.
Those. Five miles sprayed on.
The ground with the naked eye. One minute.
To minute.
About your.
Myron. Zero. Seven You lose something and.
You look over the strange.
Thing you ever saw.
My. Colleagues on the engines
mixing with in their.
Rooms the heavens with.
The man in the. Blank
beckoning fingers. In
the sky and I made.
Them in line with me to. Work
out time for them and. The
job of. Economic. Enemy
a strong skillful determined to
stop. Derided defense. Airdrome
well dispersed explain
indicates the stuff. Heavy
anti-aircraft highly trained and accurate
all along the coast and defending his
vital installations. Radar to warn
him about coming. Here is our
plan to divide his defenses and weaken
his opposition. At thirteen thirty hours
later after takeoff six groups of planes
will be heading toward the enemy coast
from six directions. The
Blue Force one hundred B.
Twenty four Liberator four engine
vomits the White Horse three hundred B.
Seventeen flying fortress the
green for three hundred B.
Seventeen with an escort of six quadrants
of people the seven Thunderbolt
a force of B.
Twenty six marauders twenty engine medium
bombers with six quadrants of Arya
Spitfires of spotting almost
a thousand planes and over
a thousand men and they have. The enemy
alerts all as they are drawn but which is
our main force what are our targets. When
should the Nazi controllers send their
fighter. It's our job to make them
guess guess wrong. A half hour later
at fourteen hundred dollars the blue force
will be heading east across the North
Sea with the white cross following. These
enemy fighters are tied down waiting to
meet them and will not be able to attack
the green for these fighters must come up
to attack the green for us and thus will
be no threat to the blue and white forces
. The B.
Twenty six is and files will bomb and spray
the key rail junction diverting viz to
stop them and preventing the enemy from
concentrating too many fighters on the
Green Party which is scheduled to
bomb an aircraft factory at kind of.
A fourteen thirty hours the blue force
will threaten this entire coastal area of
northwestern Germany. Which
target will be playing book
the Kiel Canal. A look turned suddenly
and bomb from book Vegas that for him to
actually carries no bombs at all it's
a decoys and keeps the fighters from the
northern area busy while the white boss
the main effort for the submarine Venza
Vilhelm stop. At fifteen hundred
dollars while the white
forces over its target only
a fraction of the available German fighter
strength of the carrier can intercept it
. Because of the blue force diversion and
the simultaneous bombing of kind of the
green force. This is the plan of
battle for today. Drawn up by
the combined operations planning committee.
And approved by the commanding general
. The whiteboards League group.
With the invisible line of enemy
radar. This expecting us.
Deal helmets go on watchful eyes
sprains. Formations I help title.
Ten gunners more alert
because here it comes.
From
a fear of the same as any other this is
roads green fields factories waterways. The
other houses and fields of those who invaded
the press they look back through the
road the people bison one generation
of the world with bring suffering in
such positive the history of the human
race has never. Promised an anguish to
countless American homes. And
telegrams from the water.
The first black just looking silent.
Only each of the shell exploding
from around the sky. Exactly the rain
accurate back by radio bringing in
five miles down at the end the aircraft
batteries of calculated the altitude beat
in course. The next one.
Trying not to be there.
To document the Marine.
Probes to the target. Range.
Now the enemy knows the path of Europe
from. That black browed but you fly right
through it like the Vic you can
get out and walk around it.
Can change its course every fifteen seconds
evasive action to confuse the fact
every. Time the correct
attitude be paid or
the bombing runs again.
I want to bump into
OK Then you've got it. Now given size and
the still controlling it for the bomb
site. And now we are most vulnerable.
Committed to our bombing run we can't touch
flex fight. For.
The. Defense must ignore
the battle here find
a proper target just with
the interest made. By
dining from nine o'clock. Last
night out at the range to.
See vampirism the same must be good every
other ship in the group will drop bombs
when it drops. No one point around
the bomb site another stationary
point. They. Will release.
Why.
When
a truck in. The way.
Of the mission is over they
need because. Now to get.
That beam might have someone one
that blurbing remember. Writing
a man with
a glib lines when you can see them waiting
to dive down on you right in the ground
if it were going to be the speculum night
that might have been the point that if
you firing
a new one every other round with. One
of the most important
instruments of the job.
There's an apartheid coming around.
Six o'clock upcoming entire analogy.
And your job was to flash an engine on
fire and.
Replace not
a car coming out of an. Attempt. To
make you laugh break it
into. Lack of a word to
a fuck i just trying to get
my thumb to get me to reply.
To three upper floors.
Followed.
By
a loud as one in command of. Their
going to give me my job. To
drive them home to repair your
spine with my mind and heart.
And still might be cementing the
moderate view. Of the far remarks you
have applied to me and
it's remarks. Which you.
Might use.
I'm. Finding I'm
a fucking mealy mouth jam and don't feel
the manager comes to McClaren and was
going to announce it in the
media colony gunning down on.
Their families much past.
One hundred Langham's me and mine you know
remember all around me before appearing
in.
This form for the search engine on fire
losing air speed and altitude drifting into
the black alone and coping with
strangling. Him enough to find
a spokeswoman like doesn't for the kill.
You can watch but you can't be down to
help. You keep your phone maybe.
If you had to is
a mission is being flown no less real for
being in the minds and hearts of these
men and. Ask anybody within the field
or anywhere else I promise to pay
and he'll tell you that there's drama here
too. Waiting to see who's coming back.
To watch them you might not realize how
tense these ground crews are but they are
tense and plenty worried. In Air
Force talk this waiting is known as
sweating out the mission. These men know
the fly planes their watches told them
when the bombers were running into enemy
flak when they were over the target when
they let the enemy Coast another watches
tell them the bomber should be nearing.
Every ear strange for the first sound
of the engines. And somebody hears. And
somebody sees the first plane
specks in the distance sky.
Every face Thursday. And count. Watches
trying to read the numbers on the ships.
These planes have priority to land first
the colored flares meaning wounded aboard.
The hospital window These watching men
know what that means. They know
what it feels like to live on
a boxing coach floor hundreds of miles away
for the pros the stratosphere the great
game. With the other men in your crew
fighting to keep you alive until late at the
field. The field. Will be
OK. Because they'll be medical care
the best sign of that we'll see
a plane stop rolling.
Tedward. Twenty millimeter cannon shell
exploded in his radio
compartment. Shock. Internally.
You'll be all right. Black bursts
get it flying shrapnel is full of
steel splinters. This pilot's leg is not
a pretty sight. You know
that Dr Philip. These
men will get the Purple
Heart. And this man to.
A transfusion right in the play.
This gun is too weak to be moved.
To new life giving blood flowing
into his veins might be the blood of
a high school girl in Des
Moines minor in Alabama
a movie star in Hollywood or it
might be your blood was ever it is.
Thirty six planes left this field this
morning six moron that makes twenty home
this was twenty one. More wounded aboard.
Twenty two coming in with
his left inboard engine did
what. Twenty three.
With
a feather prop on his left out Bowditch.
Twenty four so then company with
a chunk of tail gone. Twenty five.
They flew home on their luck.
Twenty six. On
a scratch. The control tower
lands the two more landed and
a British field to the side one
a crash landing crew say that
makes twenty eight. What
a night. A rough landing but
a pilot's badly heard. One
report about you know. Twenty
nine planes back so far
twenty nine of thirty six.
Losses were heavy but the enemies
were far heavier. We destroyed
a German aircraft factory
a rail junction submarine pens docks and
harbor installations that specific No one
damage but who can tell the number of
German torpedoes that will not be fired
a number of our convoys that were going
through know the soldiers and Siemens lives
that were displayed on the battle that will
be ones that have lost because of what
these bombers an airman did today.
Pilot Tejada. I can live.
Fire on the inboard
engine did this flame stick back and
burn the stabilizer to. Another crew
lock brought back.
Years old Bill. Pretty good airplane
wanted to call off the snow.
Off this navigator bombardier wounded.
Top turret gun and pilot his.
Ideology system shot out the brakes
of laches. But Old Bill came back.
Among the return crew
members talk flows like
a river talking on every detail of the
mission. These are the faces of combat
faces of Americans who have watched their
comrades die. Faces that can never forget
the enemy. In no mood is
a picture taken. In the
control tower Colonel Ray the group seal
is still watching and waiting. And he
spots the last flight three more planes.
One of them is the ship everyone's been
pulling for. Them to spill.
You to The New miles of the furthest in
a joyride strangers OK they can leave their
guns. Now they know they're going to go
home. Again Green Bay will
deploy the cargo work just as.
The bill comes in for
a landing but first Morgan for the
people at the grounds with the giant.
It's against the rules but this is
a special case. Of
. Oz.
Of.
Wheels of the Memphis the old come back to
the soil of England for the twenty fifth
. Of.
A long.
The
pharaoh
a rough eight hundred S.
a Chance to
a god. Glad
.
You're.
One. This is
a day they will never forget. Another
great day is still now Brigadier General
Counsel visited the field. And presented
the Distinguished Flying Cross
to the brim member of the group.
I'm and then there was another day.
The magistrates the king
and queen of England.
Funny when one never thought anything like
this would happen to him when he left
Yeah that's.
The ground crew were
a little self-conscious about being president
but the. But the queen thought they
were very nice.
Finally two more visitors came General Baker
commanding the labor force and general
debits U.S.
Commander of the European theater the bill
through received them in applying flow.
Of general take
a read the order of what he called their
twenty sixth and most important mission.
Return to America to train new crews to
tell of people what we're doing here to
thank them for their help and support and
told them to keep it up so we can keep it
up so we can bomb the enemy again and again
and again until we are scared enough.
And then we can all come.
Loose and blow.
Moving.
To the middle of the base there for who
are now flying deep into Germany bringing
destruction to targets almost
a thousand miles from their
bases. Destruction like this. I
do have never once been turned back by
the enemy. But those men this film is
gratefully dedicated point out.